def main(session, vk_session, longpoll, vk, random_id, event):
    
    speechDict = {
        'hello':{'question': '–ø—Ä–∏–≤–µ—Ç', 'answer': '–ü–æ—à–æ–ª —Ç—ã –Ω–∞—Ö—É–π'},
        'thx':{'question': '—Å–ø–∞—Å–∏–±–æ', 'answer': '–ü–æ—à–æ–ª —Ç—ã –Ω–∞—Ö—É–π'},
        'flat':{'question': '–Ω–∞ —Ñ–ª—ç—Ç–µ?', 'answer': '–ù–ê –§–õ–≠–¢–ï –ù–ê–•–£–£–£–£–£–ô ü§ô'},
        'rain':{'question': '–ª–∏–≤–Ω—è?', 'answer': '–î–æ–ª–±–æ–µ–±'},
        'pray':{'question': '–ø–æ–º–æ–ª–∏–º—Å—è', 'answer': 'video67219698_456244596'},
        'understand?':{'question': '–ø–æ–Ω–∏–º–∞–µ—à—å?', 'answer': 'photo-73935802_457240008'},
        'understand':{'question': '–ø–æ–Ω–∏–º–∞—é', 'answer': 'photo-73935802_457240008'},
        'you':{'question': '—Ç—ã', 'answer': '–ü–∏–¥–æ—Ä'},
        'yes':{'question': '–¥–∞', 'answer': '–ü–∏–∑–¥–∞'},
        'yes?':{'question': '–¥–∞?', 'answer': '–ü–∏–∑–¥–∞'},
        'gn':{'question': '—Å–ø–æ–∫', 'answer': '–°–ø–æ–∫!'},
        'aight':{'question': '–ª–∞–¥–Ω–æ', 'answer': '–®–æ–∫–æ–ª–∞–¥–Ω–æ, –±–ª—è'},
        'crazy':{'question': '–µ–±–∞–Ω—É—Ç—ã–π', 'answer': 'photo-73935802_457240009'},
        'popeye':{'question': '–ø–æ–ø–∞—è–Ω–Ω—ã–π', 'answer': 'photo-73935802_457240009'},
        'su':{'question': '–∑–∞–∫—Ä–æ–π —Ä–æ—Ç', 'answer': '–õ–∞–Ω'},
        'stfu':{'question': '–∑–∞–≤–∞–ª–∏ –µ–±–∞–ª–æ', 'answer': '–õ–∞–Ω'}
    }

    for key, value in speechDict.items():

        if event.obj.text.lower() == value['question']:
                if value['answer'][0:5] == 'video' or value['answer'][0:5] == 'photo':
                    inputAttach = value['answer']
                    inputMessage = ''
                else:
                    inputAttach = ''
                    inputMessage = value['answer']

                vk.messages.send(
                    random_id=random_id,
                    peer_id=event.obj.peer_id,
                    chat_id=event.chat_id,
                    message=inputMessage,
                    attachment=inputAttach
                )